Not Your Parent’s Opera
Repo! The Genetic Opera is a horror, science fiction,
music film directed by Darren Lynn Bousman.
By the year 2056, an epidemic of organ failures has devastated the planet.
The megacorporation GeneCo provides organ transplants on a payment plan - and
those who can’t fulfill their plans have their organs repossessed.
In the midst of this, a sickly teenager discovers a shocking secret
about herself, her father, and their connection to GeneCo.
Shilo Wallace, played by Alexa PenaVega.
Rotti Largo, played by Paul Sorvino.
Nathan Wallace / Repo Man, played by Anthony Stewart Head.
Blind Mag, played by Sarah Brightman.
Amber Sweet, played by Paris Hilton.
Luigi Largo, played by Bill Moseley.
The Genetic Opera is a 2008 American musical film.
Described as a gothic rock opera, the film was directed by Darren Lynn Bousman and based on the 2002
stage musical of the same name, written and composed by Darren Smith and Terrance Zdunich.
It stars Alexa Vega, Anthony Stewart Head, Sarah Brightman, Paris Hilton,
Nivek Ogre, Terrance Zdunich, Bill Moseley, and Paul Sorvino.
premiered at the Fantasia Film Festival in July 2008, followed by a limited
release on November 7, 2008, on seven screens in various cities.
The film explores themes of jealousy, dystopia, drug
addiction, heir to the throne, gore.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.